Welcome to our training on lithium batteries.
In this video, we'll show you the hazards of lithium batteries, give you the information you need
to sell lithium batteries in the Amazon store, and list the most common types of lithium batteries.
Lithium batteries are widely used in electronic products, including phones, flashlights, laptops,
and cameras.
They can enter an uncontrollable self-heating state and ignite if they're damaged, dropped, crushed,
short circuited, or exposed to heat.
For this reason, you're required to follow rules for transporting products with batteries when selling
them in the Amazon store.
We expect all sellers to partner with us to help keep our employees, carriers, and customers safe.
You must provide information about the batteries you intend to sell, including their type, weight,
quantity, composition, and number of cells.
You can add these details under battery information when you create or convert an FBA listing.
Amazon may send you an email, requiring you to complete a safety data sheet or an exemption sheet
if your product is missing required information.
You'll be expected to upload the sheet to the Manage Dangerous Goods Classification page in Seller
Central by a certain deadline.
We'll ask you to dispose of the inventory at your own expense if you miss that deadline.
But also know that incorrect battery information can result in delayed or canceled shipments.
Our team will review the requested information within two business days and let you know if we require
anything further.
Products with lithium batteries don't always include battery information on their packaging, but
there are several ways you can check your product for battery details.
You can inspect the battery for its composition details or look for them in its manufacturer's documentation,
such as the product manual.
You can also contact the supplier directly to find out what you need.
Now let's review the most common types of lithium batteries.
Lithium-ion batteries, also called Li-ion batteries, or LIBs, are rechargeable batteries that contain
lithium compounds in a liquid solution that yield energy.
Li-ion batteries are widely used in portable electronic products such as mobile phones, laptops,
tablets, MP3 players, and cameras.
Lithium-ion polymer batteries, often called lithium polymer, Li-poly, Li-pol, or Li-po batteries,
are rechargeable batteries composed of several identical secondary cells that are connected in series
and parallel.
Li-poly batteries contain lithium compounds in a polymer gel-like solution and can have a more flexible
design than lithium-ion batteries.
Li-poly batteries also have less chance of overheating.
These batteries are used in products similar to those with lithium-ion batteries.
Finally, lithium-metal batteries contain metal compounds in a solid solution and are generally not
rechargeable.
These batteries come in different shapes, including the flat, round batteries used in watches.
They're also commonly used in products such as calculators and flashlights.
For more information, search lithium batteries in Seller Central to find our help page titled Requirements
for Lithium Batteries and Products that are shipped with lithium batteries.
This concludes our overview of lithium batteries.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon store.